<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Blog Page | Ravindra Rathore - Certified Sitecore and Episerver Developer</title>
		<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog.html</link>
		<description>Generated by PolitePol.
Source page: http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog.html</description>
		<language>en</language>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:13:10 -0000</lastBuildDate>
		<item>
			<title>Possible ways to login into Episerver Commerce Manager</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2020/09/01/possible-ways-to-login-into-episerver-commerce-manager.html</link>
			<description>Hi Guys, Today I am going to tell you all the possible solutions that you can try if you don't have admin access to Episerver Commerce account using some small SQL queries. This is useful when you have restored the databases from any other server or you are working on a local environment setup for further development...</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:13:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2020/09/01/possible-ways-to-login-into-episerver-commerce-manager.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unlock locked Episerver Commerce user account</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2020/05/25/unlock-locked-episerver-commerce-user-account.html</link>
			<description>Hi Guys, Today I am going to tell you a quick way to unlock the Episerver commerce user account using a small SQL query. This is useful when your account is locked through multiple invalid password attempts. So for this, you need to find two values...</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 12:13:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2020/05/25/unlock-locked-episerver-commerce-user-account.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Use of Episerver URL property in PropertyList</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2020/04/15/use-of-episerver-url-class-in-propertyList.html</link>
			<description>Hi Guys, As you all know that some time we need to define custom properties model and then use those properties in Episerver CMS and for that we are using PropertyList.But PropertyList doesn't support complex property and we need custom implementation to support this…</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 12:13:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2020/04/15/use-of-episerver-url-class-in-propertyList.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Exclude/Disable specific items from index in Episerver Find</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/12/15/disable-indexing-for-specific-item-in-episerver-find.html</link>
			<description>Hi Guys, As you all know that Episerver Find is a preferred indexing tool for Episerver solution and we all use this in our search implementation. Sometimes we want some pages will not index in our search indexes. Like - Search Landing page itself. So today I am going to tell you the approach in…</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:58:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/12/15/disable-indexing-for-specific-item-in-episerver-find.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Categorizing the user-defined properties in All-Properties view Episerver CMS</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/11/03/categorizing-the-user-defined-properties-in-all-properties-view-episerver-cms.html</link>
			<description>Hi Guys, As you all know that Episerver provide GroupName attribute to categorizing the content based on the tabs. It's works well till we have limited property in a particular tab. But in some cases, we have lots of properties in a single tab and it's very difficult to manage these properties so we can…</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 11:43:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/11/03/categorizing-the-user-defined-properties-in-all-properties-view-episerver-cms.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Playing with Episerver webconfig settings programmatically</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/10/17/playing-with-episerver-webconfig-settings-programmatically.html</link>
			<description>Hi Guys, Sometimes we need to read, write or update some of the property from the Episerver web.config so Episerver provided a class called "EPiServerFrameworkSection". By using this class we can achieve this. I found this class very handy and I used this many times when I have to read, write and update the settings…</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 11:28:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/10/17/playing-with-episerver-webconfig-settings-programmatically.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Improve editor experience for DateTime property</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/10/05/improve-editor-experience-for-datetime-property.html</link>
			<description>Hi All, As you all know that the default DateTime widget in Episerver provides the DateTime picker. And if you want to select the date only, it still selects the time so if you want a separate field for date and time then you can use the "EditorDescriptor" to achieve this. Here is the things…</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 11:13:10 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/10/05/improve-editor-experience-for-datetime-property.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rebuild the index for selected sites in Episerver Find | Admin Tool</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/10/01/rebuild-the-index-for-selected-sites-in-episerver-find-admin-tool.html</link>
			<description>Hi Last Friday, I wrote a blog post related to "Reindex a target site in Find" using is works job. It works well but you need to update the site definition every time when you want to rebuild the indexes for any site. So I received some feedback to convert it to Episerver Admin Tool…</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 12:16:55 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/10/01/rebuild-the-index-for-selected-sites-in-episerver-find-admin-tool.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reindex a target site in Find (Schedule Job)</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/09/29/reindex-a-target-site-in-find-schedule-job.html</link>
			<description>Hey Guys, We all use Episerver Find as a search provider and it is a very handy tool for the site search. I also prefer Find over all the other search provider in Epi. But index rebuild is very time consuming if you have multiple sites hosted in the Episerver CMS. I am working on…</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 12:01:55 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/09/29/reindex-a-target-site-in-find-schedule-job.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The all new improved Paasportal on Episerver DXC services</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/09/16/the-all-new-improved-paasportal-on-episerver-dxc-services.html</link>
			<description>Hi All, If you haven't visited the Paasportal in last few days or weeks then there are some new features those are added in Paasportal can be very handy for the developers More tabs for the categorization Now you will see these three tabs- DeploymentsHostnamesTroubleshoot Deployments tab Deployment This tab has the deployment options from…</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 11:46:55 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/09/16/the-all-new-improved-paasportal-on-episerver-dxc-services.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An easy way to manage static text in Episerver CMS</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/09/11/an-easy-way-to-manage-static-text-in-episerver-cms.html</link>
			<description>Hi All, Today, I am writing a blog post to create a dictionary block to manage static text like - "Read More, Learn more, View More, etc...". This is very helpful when you have multiple CTA blocks or pages those have this kind of static text and you want to give the control to the…</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:31:55 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/09/11/an-easy-way-to-manage-static-text-in-episerver-cms.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Retrieving absolute url of current page on any page or block | Episerver</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/08/02/retrieving-absolute-url-of-current-page-on-any-page-or-block.html</link>
			<description>Hi, If you've ever tried to get the full URL of a current page then this blog post may come handy. So basically you will need VirtualPathArguments, That will have ContextMode facility to enable it based on our needs. For instance Default mode, Edit mode, Preview mode and obviously an Undefined mode if the Context…</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 11:16:55 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/08/02/retrieving-absolute-url-of-current-page-on-any-page-or-block.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Disallow duplicate items in the Episerver ContentArea Property</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/07/22/disallow-duplicate-items-in-the-episerver-contentarea-property.html</link>
			<description>Hey guys, In past i learned about the validation attributes and to try it out i have created a validation attribute for disabling the duplicate items(page/block/media) in the ContentArea property. Yesterday some of my colleague asked me about this so thought to write this post. So first of all i have created a class called…</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 12:20:22 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/07/22/disallow-duplicate-items-in-the-episerver-contentarea-property.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Render Episerver Page Item tree on View</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/06/24/render-episerver-page-item-tree-on-view.html</link>
			<description>Hi All, I have a scenario in our website where I need to display the Episerver tree on our view. Like- So I thought that we can use the "GetDescendents" method and it will render the tree but i was wrong. It basically give you all the page items in a single list so you…</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 12:05:22 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/06/24/render-episerver-page-item-tree-on-view.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Adding a Start Page | Episerver for beginners</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/03/14/adding-a-start-page-episerver-for-beginners.html</link>
			<description>Hey Guys, To create first page type in your EmptySite solution that is created in my last blog post. Please follow the below steps- Open the EmptySite solution in visual studio.Right click on the pages folder inside Models-&gt;Pages. Please refer below screenshot for reference. Now click Add-&gt; New Item.Now select "Episerver" template from installed template.Then…</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 11:50:22 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/03/14/adding-a-start-page-episerver-for-beginners.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hosting a Episerver site in IIS | Episerver for beginners</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/02/21/hosting-a-episerver-site-in-iis-episerver-for-beginners.html</link>
			<description>Hey guys, In today’s post, I will describe how to host an Episerver site in the IIS. In my last post, I have created two solutions one is blank site and one Alloy site so I am using the alloy site for this blog post. First of all, you have to attach the Episerver databases…</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 11:35:22 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/02/21/hosting-a-episerver-site-in-iis-episerver-for-beginners.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Creating your first solution | Episerver for beginners</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/01/29/creating-your-first-solution-episerver-for-beginners.html</link>
			<description>Hi guys, If you are new to Episerver and wanted to start your career in the Episerver then you can refer my blog series to learn some basic thing of Episerver. Please refer my first blog post if you already not referred this configure-your-development-environment-episerver-for-beginners/ Once you are done with your configuration then move forward with…</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:20:22 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/01/29/creating-your-first-solution-episerver-for-beginners.html</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Getting Started | Episerver for beginners</title>
			<link>http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/01/10/configure-your-development-environment-episerver-for-beginners.html</link>
			<description>Hey guys, I am writing a blog series on episerver cms development for beginner. So here is my first blog post about the basic configuration/software required for Episerver development. These are the two things that we need to start the development in Episerver- 1. Microsoft Visual Studio 2015 or 2017 (with latest updates) 2. Episerver…</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 11:05:22 -0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ravindrarathore.com/blog/2019/01/10/configure-your-development-environment-episerver-for-beginners.html</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>